This display is all about Professor William Buckland
Who was a scientist here at Oxford University in the 19th century
Buckland called himself an 'undergroundologist'
because he was so fascinated by the world beneath his feet.
He became one of the first ever proper geologists
For thousands of years, people believed that life here on Earth
had continued pretty much the same ever since it first appeared.
But Buckland's discoveries changed our perception of the past.
He studied fossils. Many of them found here in Oxfordshire, and some exhibited right here in this museum.
He used those fossils as a way of showing how life on Earth had changed over millions of years.