In 1822, William Buckland crawled in Kirkdale Cave in Yorkshire
There he found the bones of hyaenas, along with bones of some of the animals they had eaten.
He even found their poo!
You can see some of their incredibly impressive teeth here in this case.
To Buckland, these fossils were evidence that hyaenas must once have lived here in England.
Even more than that, they were evidence of how our world changes over time.
Today, hyaenas are only found in hot, dry savannahs in Africa, and certainly not in caves here in England
So at some stage in the past, England must have been hotter and drier than it is today.
Even further in the past, it would have been wetter and more tropical than it is today.