This case is all about Megalosaurus
It was a giant, 9-meter long lizard
That roamed around Oxfordshire around about a hundred and sixty million years ago
But how do we know this? I mean, even I'm not that old!
Well, this was first found by William Buckland, who was a geologist in the 19th century.
He quickly realised what he had
but also there were no 9-metre long carnivorous lizards wandering around Oxfordshire
So, he reasoned that at some time in the past, they must have been here but had gone extinct.
As other bones were discovered, all around the country and all around the planet,
The name 'Dinosaur' was thought up to describe them
So, here in this case, we have the first described bones of any dinosaur
and they show how much our wildlife, and our planet, has changed through its long history