We have some fossils here that are not from dinosaurs, but from marine reptiles.
Unlike dinosaurs, these lived in the oceans.
Victorian fossil hunter Mary Anning discovered many of these,
and so she was known as the 'princess of palaeontology'
which is the study of fossils.
She found Ichthyosaurs, Plesiosaurs and Pterosaurs
many of them at Lyme Regis on the south coast of England
In Mary's time, many people refused to believe these creatures had ever been alive.
They thought the remains had been put there just to confuse us.
Or that some mystical life force had found its way into the rocks.
Mary helped to prove these creatures had been living, because she found their fossilised poo.
This is known to scientists as 'coprolites'.
Only living things poo so these animals must, at some stage, have been alive.