We all know that no two human beings look exactly the same,
but we also know that we belong to just one species. Humans, or 'Homo sapiens'
Animals of the same species may look similar, but not identical to each other
There are always going to be differences in size, shape,
colour, and what they can and can't do. Even in their behaviour
This display behind me has a variety of different colours of moths and snails,
but there's only one species of snail, and one species of moth here.
The differences between animals of the same species are called 'variations'.
and sometimes a variation can help one animal to survive better than another.
Stronger legs, better eyesight, or better camouflage, such as is found in the moths here
can be the difference between life and death
and here's the crucial bit -
An animal that survives and has babies, can pass on its features or its characteristics to its young.
In just the same way as you'll have some characteristics you've inherited from your parents.
An animal that has an unlucky variation, won't be able to survive and have babies at all,
so it won't pass on any of its characteristics.
In the next stop on the trail we'll find out quite what a big difference this can make.