Charles Darwin is famous for his theory of evolution.
Evolution explains how plants and animals slowly change over long periods of time into new species.
It's a clever and complicated idea that Darwin worked on for many years.
But what does it have to do with these pigeons?
You've just seen how small variations between animals of the same species might make one animal more likely to survive than another.
That animal may pass on its characteristics to its young.
However, if an animal doesn't survive long enough to have babies,
those characteristics could be lost from the species altogether.
This happens in nature, but people can make it happen too.
If you kept and bred pigeons and only allowed the ones with speckled wings to have babies,
you'd be much more likely to have pigeon babies with speckled wings.
If you kept on doing this, eventually all of your pigeons would be speckled.
Darwin did this with his own pigeons
He realised that while some species will have characteristics which are passed on or disappear in nature,
species will change very slowly and with time
This is all because small variations can change an animal's chances of passing on its characteristics.
This, he called 'natural selection'.