In the museum you'll see dazzling examples of birds and reptiles
that occur in almost every environment on planet Earth.
They're at home on land, in the sea, even in the sky.
Because they've adapted over hundreds of millions of years to be at home in that environment.
In the Sensing Evolution trail you'll see how small variations from one generation to the next
can add up to very big changes over long periods of time.
Animal life first emerged in the oceans hundreds of millions of years ago.
Eventually some animals were able to live on land
because they evolved hard, scaly skins which didn't dry out so much.
They also got the ability to lay eggs on the ground with hard, protective shells.
These were the reptiles.
Today's birds and reptiles evolved from an ancient lizard-like creature
which looked something like the common lizard you can see in the centre of the Sensing Evolution table.
This process began around 320 million years ago
Since then they have adapted into all of the many forms you can see around the table.