This is a very famous fossil.
It's of a creature called Archaeopteryx and it's an estimated 160 million years old.
The reason that it's so famous and so important is that when it was found
it was the oldest known example of any animal with feathers.
If you look closely you can see the feathery imprints in the rock here.
It's believed that Archaeopteryx may have been the first of the birds to evolve from the dinosaurs.
Since then, birds have evolved into the approximately ten thousand different species that we have in the world today.
There are some spectacular examples of them right here in this museum.
But Archaeopteryx is important because it shows us the beginnings of that long process of evolution.
That the birds we see around us today are in fact living dinosaurs.