I have here a cast of an extremely famous fossil.
The fossil of Archaeopteryx, one of the earliest known birds.
Archaeopteryx has a lot in common with modern birds.
It has a light skeleton, it has long arm bones in its wings,
and of course, it has feathers for flying.
and scans of its skull reveal that the areas of the brain associated with vision and balance were enlarged.
Very useful if you're an animal that flies.
But, there are also odd things about this skeleton of Archaeopteryx
Things which link it back to its dinosaur ancestors.
Archaeopteryx, unlike modern birds, has little sharp teeth.
It has three clawed fingers within its wing and it has a long, bony tail
So as an extremely early bird, Archaeopteryx shows more traces of its dinosaur ancestors than our modern birds today