Do you like Brussels sprouts? Some people do, and some people don't.
Can you roll your tongue?
Again, some people can and some people can't.
Even though we're all members of the same species, <i>Homo sapiens</i>
we're all different to each other.
Even offspring of the same parents are genetically different
and genetic variation is fundamental to life and the way that life evolves.
Our genetic code is carried by this molecule.
This is DNA
or deoxyribonucleic acid
and variation is introduced into this molecule in a number of different ways.
In sexually reproducing animals, like us
we create variety by making sex cells, eggs and sperm
with unique combinations of genes from each parent.
But there can also be mutations. This means changes to the units
the nucleotides that make up the DNA.
This can happen because of copying errors,
or because of damage to the DNA.
Mutations sound like bad news
but in fact they're crucial to creating variety
and without them evolution would virtually grind to a halt.
It's evolution that has created the diversity of life on the planet
and allowed life to evolve and adapt to changing environments.