Fossil evidence clearly shows us that life on the planet
hasn't always looked the way it does today.
Take horses for example.
The ancestors of our modern horses looked completely different
and we know that because we have a fantastic fossil record
stretching back around 60 million years.
The ancestors of horses were small creatures
with several toes and they lived in rainforests.
Their small size would have meant that they could hide in the undergrowth
and their splayed toes meant that they could walk on marshy ground.
But then the environment changed. The forest started to disappear and grassland spread out
and horses adapted to this changing environment.
They became larger, taller, longer-legged and fleet of foot.
They were able to range widely across the grasslands eating enough grass
but also being able to run away fast from predators.
And just think about horses' legs today.
They don't have this many toes.
In fact, they've reduced down to a single toe on each leg.
A single toe, and a single hoof.