The Snowy Owl has incredible hearing and eyesight
near silent flight, feathered talons, and of course it's white.
These are all incredibly valuable features for an Arctic predator.
And they're the result of natural selection acting on countless generations of Snowy Owls.
Parents with characteristics which helped them survive and reproduce
would be most likely to pass on those characteristics to their offspring.
We think that natural selection is even acting on the size of the Snowy Owl as well,
because average sized owls tend to have the most offspring.
This might all be about energy.
Larger owls might have too much of an energy demand to have plenty of offspring.
Smaller owls might not get enough larger prey
and so natural selection favours an optimum body weight
where more offspring will be produced.
Natural selection acts on every single species on the planet
and we see a wonderful range of animals adapted to all sorts of different environments.
And of course, natural selection and evolution is still happening.