In his 1971 book, The Descent of Man, Charles Darwin suggested
that humans were descended from ancestral African apes
Now since then, many fossils of ancestral human-like species have been discovered
We have about twenty of these species now
and all of these "hominins", as we call them
are more closely related to us humans
than they are to African apes like chimpanzees and gorillas.
One of the most famous Hominin species is Australopithecus aforensis
and one of the most famous fossils of that species is called "Lucy"
and she was discovered in 1974 in Ethiopia
And in fact there was much more of Lucy's skeleton than I've got represented here
We have about 40% of her skeleton
and that's enough to see that there are important differences
between her skeleton and that of
living African apes like chimpanzees and gorillas
and those differences relate to the way in which she moved around.
We know from looking at her skeleton
that Lucy was adapted to walking upright on two legs.