Reproduction is key to the survival of any species.
Even amongst mammals, we find differences in reproductive strategies.
Some species like us humans tend to have just a few offspring
and we look after them very carefully
and this improves their chances of surviving to adulthood.
Other species have a very different strategy
and they have many, many offspring
A really good example of that is the shrew
A female shrew has between 15 and 28 offspring
in every breeding season.
In every single litter, there is going to be variation.
Those offspring are going to differ from each other.
Some individuals are going to be better suited to the environment that they're born into
and they'll have a better chance of survival.
So this is what's known as "survival of the fittest".
But natural selection doesn't stop there.
Because even amongst the shrews that survive to adulthood, there will be varying numbers of offspring.
So natural selection is actually about survival <i><b>and</i></b> reproduction.