As we've seen with the Snowy Owl, all living things compete for the resources they need
to survive and reproduce.
But there's much more to reproduction than just having enough energy to produce offspring
You need to attract a mate
One way of doing is to show off.
A very good example of that is the peacock's tail.
Peahens prefer peacocks with flamboyant tails with plenty of eye spots.
so over time, the peacock's tail has become more and more extravagant.
This is what's known as sexual selection.
In comparison with the peacock, the peahen is drab.
That's an advantage to her when she's sitting on her nest keeping her eggs warm.
So over countless generations, the effects of sexual selection and natural selection
have exaggerated the difference between males and females.
Between peacocks and peahens.