Charles Darwin is probably the most famous biologist of all time.
This museum opened in 1860, just a year after Darwin published the book that would make him famous
<i>On the Origin of Species</i>.
In it, he described how a completely natural process
a process he called "natural selection"
could shape life on the planet
and through gradual change, produce millions of different species.
Darwin wasn't the only biologist thinking and writing about evolution in the 19th century
but he described how evolution could happen.
and that was a real breakthrough.
He also wrote for a general audience.
<i>On the Origin of Species</i> wasn't a book written to be read by scientists
it was a popular science book.
It was so widely read that Darwin quickly became world famous.